

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Ali MASRI

- Versailles (France)
- **+1** (320) 317 5412
- x alimasri1991@gmail.com
- alimasri.github.io
- Skype alimasri1991

Sex Male | Date of birth 02/07/1991 | Nationality Lebanese

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a Data Scientist specialized in Deep Learning, Machine Learning and Big Data (Storage, Processing and Analysis). I have a strong research and professional background with a Ph.D. degree in Computer Science from the University of Paris-Saclay and VEDECOM institute. I practice my skills through R&D, consultancy and by providing data science trainings.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/01/2020-Present

Data scientist

Intelligencia, Paris (France)

www.intelligencia.fr

- Al and Big Data Research and Development
 - □ Helped in adopting the most recent technologies and keeping the company up-to-date
 - $\hfill \square$ Successfully accomplished many projects while leading the data science team
- Consultant
 - Guided many customers to optimize their data infrastructure performance by proposing the best technologies, tools and architectures
- Trainer
 - □ Taught many trainees detailed concepts and practices in Big Data, Data Science and AI

01/11/2017-30/11/2019

Data Scientist

Cognitus, Paris (France)

www.cognitus.fr

- Al and Big Data Research and Development
 - □ Helped in adopting the most recent technologies and keeping the company up-to-date
 - □ Successfully accomplished many projects while leading the data science team
- Consultant
 - Guided many customers to optimize their data infrastructure performance by proposing the best technologies, tools and architectures
- Trainer
 - □ Taught many trainees detailed concepts and practices in Big Data, Data Science and AI

2015–2017 Researcher

VEDECOM, Versailles (France)

www.vedecom.fr

- Research on transportation multimodality for smart cities
- Proposed a new model to make multimodality easier to implement and maintain
- Proposed a three-level integration solution on:



Curriculum vitae Ali MASRI

- □ Schema level
- □ Data level
- □ Services level
- Implemented many software libraries as multimodal integration solutions
- Published many articles in international conferences and journals

01/2016-12/2016

Backend and Mobile Developer - JAX-RS, Struts2, Android

Logixy, Paris (France)

- Designed and implemented a database and business process for an Intelligent Transport Management System
- Adopted a service oriented architecture
- Created a web and mobile applications

06/2015-12/2015

Java Developer

3iConsulting, Palaiseau (France)

- Maintained and solved many bugs in a pre-built production solution
- Made the product easier by developing many helper tools

06/2015-12/2015

PHP Developer

Nouvelle Génération Médicale (NGM), Paris (France)

 Increased the association popularity by creating and maintaining a website + blog for the French association "Nouvelle Génération Médicale (NGM)"

02/2014-07/2014

Research and Development

UVSQ and 3iConsulting, Versailles (France)

- Master thesis in supply chain management and service oriented architecture
- Helped the company in adopting a service oriented architecture by designing and implementing the new solution

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Ph. D. in Computer Science

Université Paris-Saclay, Paris (France)

Masters in Information and Decision Support Systems

Lebanese University Faculty of Sciences, Beirut (Lebanon)

Bachelors Degree in Computer Science

Lebanese University Faculty of Sciences, Beirut (Lebanon)

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Arabic

Foreign language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C1	C1	C1

English

Curriculum vitae Ali MASRI

French

A2 A2 A2 A2 A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Communication skills

- Very good communication and presentation skills gained through my experience as a Ph.D. and as data science trainer in addition to working with international clients and teams
- Very good mentoring and training skills gained through my experience as a Data Science trainer
- Very good consultancy skills
- Very good writing skills. My research papers were published in many international conferences and journals, and I still write for online data science publications (Towards Data Science, The Startup, Heartbeat, Marktechpost)

Organisational / managerial skills

 Leadership: I have experience in leading and mentoring many development and data science team members

Job-related skills

■ Mentoring skills (Supervised many interns and students in my courses)

Digital skills

	SELF-ASSESSMENT					
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem- solving		
Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user		

Digital skills - Self-assessment grid

- Very good in machine learning and deep learning on both conceptual and engineering levels
- Very good in big data storage, processing and analysis
- Very good programming skills
- Programming Languages
 - □ Python
 - □ JAVA
- Big Data Technologies and Tools
 - □ Hadoop
 - □ Hive
 - □ Cloudera Distribution
 - □ Spark
 - □ Elastic Stack
- Deep Learning and Machine Learning Libraries
 - □ Scikit-learn
 - □ Keras
 - □ Tensorflow
 - □ Spark MILib
- Docker
- Relational Databases
- NoSQL Databases
 - □ MongoDB
- Other tools
 - □ Git
 - □ Latex





□ MS Office Products

Driving licence

В

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Projects

- Big Data ETL System with Versioning
- Sales Prediction
- Disguise Detection
- Lebanese License Plate Recognition
- Advanced Document Manager with OCR and Quick Search
- Smart Glasses for Security Forces

Certifications

- IBM Data Science Specialization
- <u>Deep Learning Specialization by deeplearning.ai</u> (5 Course Certificate)
- Machine Learning by Standford University on Coursera
- Google Developer Certification Associate Android Developer

Online Publications

I like writing about various data science concepts in intuitive ways for the public. After some introductory courses I had the honor to write for many online publications:

- Towards Data Science
- Heartbeat
- The Startup
- Marktechpost

A compilation of my articles can be found on my blog: http://alimasri.github.io

Research Publications

- Ali Masri. Multi-Network integration for an Intelligent Mobility. Ph.D. Thesis.
- Ali Masri, Karine Zeitouni and Zoubida Kedad. Retry: Integrating ridesharing with existing trip planners. SIGSPATIAL2017
- Ali Masri, Karine Zeitouni, Zoubida Kedad and Bertrand Leroy. An Automatic Matcher and Linker for Transportation Datasets. ISPRS2017
- Ali Masri, Karine Zeitouni, Zoubida Kedad and Bertrand Leroy. Automatic Detection and Mapping of Geospatial Properties in Transportation Data Sources. SIGSPATIAL2016
- Ali Masri, Karine Zeitouni, Zoubida Kedad, Bertrand Leroy and Gabriel Kepeklian. Discovering Multimodal Routes using Connection Patterns. ITSC2016
- Ali Masri, Karine Zeitouni, Zoubida Kedad and Gabriel Kepeklian. Link++: A flexible and customizable tool for connecting RDF data sources. ESWC2016
- Fatima Abdallah, Hassan Sbeyti, Ali Masri, Malak Khreis, Hussein Hazimeh, Mohamed Dbouk, and Ahmad Fadlallah: unified Sensor interface for Context-Aware Mobile aPplications (SCAMP). The Lebanese Association of Advanced Sciences LAAS20
- Hamid Mcheick, Raef Mousheimish, Ali Masri, Youssef Dergham: Context Aware Collaborative Computing Model for Natural Disaster Management Systems. HCI (21) 2014: 439-449

Honours and awards

■ Placed 4th in the Lebanese Collegiate Programming Competition